Juan Jesús Espinosa Martínez

Mérida, Spain · <u>/in/juan-jesus-espinosa-martinez/</u> · +34 677779235 · jjespinosamartinez@gmail.com

+3 years of experience as a Full Stack developer. I easily adapt to circumstances, enjoy teamwork and I am always willing to learn. Moreover, new challenges are my principal source of motivation.

EXPERIENCE

IOONFull Stack Developer

(Remote) Mérida, Spain

December 2024 – Present

Responsibilities

- Design and implement new use cases (UC) focused on conversion rate optimisation (CRO) based on data-driven decisions.
- Ensure the correct feeding of the **customer data platform (CDP)** with data of user interactions for the creation of **audiences**.
- Be the reference person for Back-End (Node.js/Express.js, FastAPI, API design, database design...) and Front-End (Dynamic Yield, Figma, React, UI/UX design, Tailwind CSS...) technologies and take initiative to learn new ones.
- Make an impact on the whole team by proactively supporting other team members, helping them and looking for ways to improve the team processes.

Key accomplishments

- Proactively redesigned, using Figma, a marketing campaign (Pop up with lead generation form)
 distributed across all Stellantis brands and countries, improving responsiveness and user interface
 (UI) and adding micro-interactions and animations (GSAP), which led to a significant increase in conversion.
- Developed use cases ('Abandoned Configuration') in Dynamic Yield using cookies with the aim of bringing the user back to the point where they left their vehicle configuration, which significantly increased conversion.
- Proposed and led the development of a REST API based on Express.js (Node.js) as a dynamic solution
 to a problem affecting numerous outdated marketing campaigns, which increased the revenue from
 those campaigns.
- Led the implementation of **Dynamic Yield (Consent scripts, Page Context, Product Feed...)** on the new Stellantis pages in order to use the advanced features of this tool.
- Deployed and monitored scripts in **Google Tag Manager** to collect emails from users entered in forms and feed the **customer data platform (CDP)**.

SOLUTE

Badajoz, Spain

Full Stack Developer

October 2022 - December 2024

Responsibilities

- Be the reference person for Back-End (Node.js/Express.js, FastAPI, API design, database design...)
 and Front-End (React, UI/UX design, Tailwind CSS...) technologies and take initiative to learn new
 ones.
- Design and implement medium to large size features while reducing the system's tech debt.
- Make an impact on the whole team by proactively supporting other team members, helping them and looking for ways to improve the team processes.

Key accomplishments

• Collected the **requirements** and led the design of the **REST API** of a new internal product, which led to a huge improvement in developers' **productivity**.

- Joined a team from GE Vernova that worked with SCRUM methodology as the reference Back-End developer. Led the technical design of the REST API new features and highly improved its performance and security by updating its framework to the latest LTS version and introducing new technologies, such as database migrations.
- Led the development of a **React**-based extension for another company's platform. In addition to the success of the project, the collaboration between both companies was strengthened for future developments.
- Redesigned weather forecasting team's website User Interface (UI) which had a huge impact on User Experience (UX).
- Redesigned the weather forecasting team's REST API using the **FastAPI Python** framework.
- Defined the team's version control strategy and set up the continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) flow in Gitlab for all the team's projects.
- Deployed a new centralized download system for numerical weather models (developed in Python and connected to a **SQL** database for tracking and control) for the forecasting team.

EDUCATION

University of Extremadura

Mérida, Spain

Computer Engineering in Information Technologies / Telematics Engineering in Telecommunications

2017 - 2022

University of the West of Scotland

Paisley, Glasgow, UK

Computer Networking

2019 - 2020

COURSES

- React The Complete Guide 2023 (incl. React Router & Redux)
- Figma UI UX Design Essentials

SKILLS

• React

JavaScript

UI/UX Design

TypeScript

Express.js

Python

FastAPI

REST API

SQL / NoSQL

• Tailwind CSS

Node.js

Java

CI / CD

• Git

Astro

LANGUAGES

• My first language is Spanish. Fluid in English (C1).